Finding Aid for the Farington Family Correspondence LSC.0668
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Folio 2
  - Manuscript containing notes and transcriptions from religious writings given by M. Church to William Farington, 1802 July (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Next six pages contain verses entitled "Description of an Hermit", followed by 40 pages of prose, mostly of a religious nature, ending with the note, "Let every word that my hand has traced witness for me when you are far distant-how earnestly and affectionately I wish your happiness, brother here and hereafter. M.C., Clifton, July 19th 1802".
- Folio 3
  - Binder Covers, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1782-3, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    First letter addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton" with Postal stamp, "17 May 1831" and signed "Mund or Jack or [?] or whatever you choose to call me..." Caricature at bottom of final page, seems to be in juvenile script.
    Second letter headed, "Madrass Roads 16th May 1783", with salutatory "My de[are?]st Life" and signed "Wm Farington"; discusses Brazil, China, and Bombay.
    Third letter unsigned but in same hand and with same ink as previous letter, heading: "St. Salvador in the Bay of all Saints on the Coast of Brazil Lat. 13.00 South-Wednesday, 11th December, 1782" begins, "My wonderful love, This will be the first letter that it has been in my power to send to thee, for when Lord [?] left us, he to proceed to Gibraltar us to the East Indies, we had not the least previous notice..."
    Following that is a section or draft of a letter, dated "Tuesday, 17th December 1782", signed vertically "of the most affectionate love of thy Husband, Wm Farington". Paper is folded in half over previous three items to produce an informal packet, and on the front of this piece of paper is written in pencil "Brazil".
  - Correspondence, 1784, 1814-1815, 1841 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    First letter is from William Farington to his wife, header: "Ship General loot 5th February 178[4?]", and references China.
    Second letter is cross-written and dated Oct. 19 with postal stamps for 1814, and is addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain". It contains remnants of a red wax seal and hole were seal was once affixed.
    Third letter is headed "Br[?]lles, [Dec?] 29" with a postal stamp: "Jan W 7 M 1815". It is cross-written and addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain".
    Fourth letter is cross-written, with header, "Br[?]lles, Dec. 13" and contains postal stamps: "DEC W 30 M 1814" and "DE A 27 1814". It is addressed to "Mrs. Farington, Post Office, Edinburgh, N. Britain" and a Red wax seal of a boar still affixed.
    Fifth letter has header, Worden, March 18th 1841" and is signed "Yours very faithfully, [I/J?] Nowell Farington". It is addressed to "W. Farington, Esq., Woodvale, Cowes, Isle of Wight" and contains postal stamps: "Chorley: M 18, 184[?] and "19 MR 1841". The paper on which it is written contains the watermark "J Whatman 1838" and the remnants of a black wax seal is still attached. Letter shares condolences for the death of Farington's sister. Fifth letter is a single sheet of paper containing a letter or draft of a letter, signed "William Farrington" with the salutation "My dear love".
  - Correspondence to William Farington from his younger siblings Edmund, Richard, and Frances, 1829, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    First letter has header, "Warfield Sunday 18th, 1829" and is addressed to "Mr. W. Farington, Commoners, Winton" with postal stamp "1829" and watermark "G & R Turner 1826" and begins, "Dear William will you be so good as to send me a needle and mesh..."
    Second letter has header, "Warfield, May 10 1829" and is addressed to "Mr. W Farington, Commoners Winchester", with watermark "G and R Turner 1827" and is signed: "believe me my Dearest Brother ever to remain yours affectionately, Edmund Farington".
    Third letter is undated (though the paper has the watermark "1829"), is addressed to "William" and is signed "your most affectionate sister Frances Ann Farington".
    The fourth letter has header "Warfield, Tues, Oct 4, 1831" and is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton". It is signed "Ever yours, [E?] Farrington". In a second hand, which is large, within pencil ruling, juvenile, and calligraphic is written: "My dear William I hope you are quite well..." and is signed "your R A F."
    The fifth letter has header "Warfield, Sunday, Sept 25 1831" with postal stamp "D. 27 Sept. 1831" and is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton". It is written in two hands and signed by both "E. Farington" and "R.A.F".
    The sixth letter has header, "Warfield, Sunday May 31st 1829, and is signed "Edmund Farington" and addressed to "Mr. William Farington, Commoners, Winchester"
    it is followed by a small note, signed "C. Faithfull" and addressed to "Master Farrington" and invites him to a birthday celebration.
    The eighth letter has header "Warfield, Sund. Oct 15, 1831", is addressed to "Mr. Farington, Commoners, Winton" and is written in two hands, signed "[?].F. and R.A. Farington".
    The ninth letter has header "Warfield, Sunday 8 1829", contains a list of names and red wax seal, and is addressed to "W. Farrington at the Rev. Dr. Williams, Commoners, Winchester" and is signed "E. Farington". The tenth letter has a black border and is signed your "very affectionate Sister, Frances Ann Farington". It is undated in the original ink hand, but in pencil is written, "Nov. 6 1829".
  - Correspondence to William Farington from younger siblings, Edmund, Frances Ann and Richard, his friend William Macgregor, and his mother, 1825, 1827-1829 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    First letter is written in a large, juvenile, calligraphic hand within pencil ruling to "My dear Willy" and is signed "your affect[ionate] brother Richard, Nov. 26, 1829".
    The second letter is written to William from his sister Frances Ann Farrington and in a different hand and ink is headed "Wood Vale, October 21st 1829".
    The third letter is has header, "14 Saville Row London" and, in pencil "July 1828" and is signed "Your affectionate schoolfellow, William Macgregor".
    The fourth letter has header "Woodvale July 22 1827" and is addressed to William Farington at two different locations (Isle of Wight and Warfield) from his mother. It contains an ink sketch of a ship and sailing flag.
    The fifth letter to William Farington from his mother, "J.A. Farington, Woodvale May 31, 1827". This is followed by a scrap of paper containing notes and a red seal.
    Sixth letter has header "Woodvale February 24th '25" and is from Edmund; contains postal stamp "D 25FF25 1825" and red wax seal.
  - Correspondence from William Farington to his wife Fanny., 1814 May 02 - June 07 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1814 July 06 - 17 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Though not signed, appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife. Contains entries for correspondence and verse. The scrap of paper intermingled with the pages contains the address "HMS Clio off [?] July 15th / [Mrs./Wm?]Farington" and a street address in [Edinbury?].
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1814 July 17 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Appears to be a continuation of the correspondence in the previous folder. Contains both verse and prose, and one sheet contains the date "Sunday [Morn.?] July 17th 1814 and the address [Mrs.?] Farington / M[r/rs?] Me[?]'s Lodgings / Princess Street / Edinbu[ry?]".
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1814 July 28 - August 06 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife Fanny--contains both prose and verse addressed to her.
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1814 September 16 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1818 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Appears to be correspondence from William Farington to his wife --contains both prose and verse addressed to her. Throughout the pages are small sketches.
  - Personal Correspondence of William Farington, 1814-1815 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Correspondence from William Farington to his wife.
- Folio 4
  - Poster used as Binder, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Poster reproduction of 1892 painting "Bonnie Prince Charlie" by the Royal Academian John Pattie
    at top margin, "Supplement to 'Holly Leaves,' The Christmas Number of 'The Illustrated Sporting and Dramatic news,' November 20, 1939."
    Folded in two ad used as an informal binder for correspondence items.
    On backside of poster is written in pencil, "To Joseph Farington from his father, Rev. W.F." (i.e. Rev. William Farington (d. 1767), not to be confused with his son William Farington (d. 1803), or his grandson of the same name, whose correspondences are also included in the collection).
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, 1762 January 26; 1763 June 21 - November 29 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, future Royal Academian, while he was studying art under Mr. Wilson in London.
    The letters discuss personal expenses, London life, and Joseph's drawings, and impart fatherly advice.
    Two letters (dated: October 6th 1763 and November 15th, 1763) discuss specific pieces of artwork Joseph had sent home, including sketches of Hercules, ruins, Christ, and St. Paul.
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, 1764 January 20 - December 18 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, while he was studying art in London.
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, 1764 (October 25th?) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Personal correspondence.
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, 1764 June 16 - 1767 July 12 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Eleven letters, showing various degrees of wear and tearing, all but one of which are dated. These letters, which are from Rev. William Farington to his son Joseph, mostly date from the years 1766-1767 and are addressed to several locations:
    "The Rev. Mr. Jacobs in Long Acre, London",
    "Mrs. Luthers in Thrift-Street, Soho, London",
    "Mrs. Macquoy's in York Buildings, Strand,"
    "Mr. Wilsons, Painter, the Great Piazza, Covent Garden, London".
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to son Joseph Farington, 1765 June 21 - December 19 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Letters discuss personal affairs, finances, and art.
  - Correspondence to Joseph Farington from father Rev. William Farington and brother George Farington, 1765 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Folio 5
  - Poster used as Binder, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    On backside of poster is written in pencil, "To Will Farington from his father- Rev W.F."
    To this poster was attached by paper clip a small piece of paper on which is written "Misc. Mss. 100/x8 Farington 4"
  - Correspondence from Rev. William Farington to his son William Farington, 1762 March 16 - 1766 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Mostly correspondence from Rev. William Farington to his son William Farington, addressed to several locations, including, Broad Street, London
    on board the Reward, Captain Richard Saunders, Outward Bound, at Falmouth
    on board the Neptune
    on board the Egmont.
    In addition to Rev. Farington's letters to his son, there is a letter labeled by the younger William Farington, "Copy of a Letter from my Father to Mr. Jonathan Brideoake about my going to Sea, Leigh 3rd August 1762", as well as the draft of a letter, possibly to William's captain, dated 28 November 1762.
- Folio 6
  - Poster used as Binder, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    In pencil, "Farrington Misc Letters not relating to Joseph F."
  - Correspondence between Rev. William Farington and his nephew William Farington, 1756 March 29 - 1772 January 10 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Dates of letters are:
    Jan 31, 1761 (from nephew William Farington regarding his recommendation for the position of Sheriff)
    March 29 1756
    August 6, 1765
    April 22, 1767
    Jan 10, 1772 (from uncle to nephew regarding his own serious illness)
    and December 4, 1764.
  - Correspondence between William Farington and George Farington, 1773 November 08 - 1778 April 19 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    September 7, 1777
    November 30, 1777
    April 19, 1778
    November 8, 1773.
  - Farington Family Correspondence, 1767 June 10 - 1785 January 29 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    July 30, 1769 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William)
    November 28, 1777 (William Farington to cousin William Farington)
    September 22, 1779 (William Farington to cousin William Farington)
    May 28, 1780 (William Farington to cousin William Farington)
    December 8, 1772 (William Farington to cousin William Farington)
    June 5, 1774 (R.A. Farington to his mother)
    June 10, 1767 (from Lucy Wright to her brother)
    January 29 1785 (to Edward Farington from a brother?)
    March 6, 1774 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William)
    June 3, 1776 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William)
    January 31 1773 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William)
    and December 11, 1772 (Elizabeth Farington to her son William).
- Folio 7
  - Poster used as Binder, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Labeled at bottom "The Times. Map of the North-Eastern Theatre of War"; in pencil on back, "Will of Rev. W. Farington (Father of Joseph F.) and other papers, letters, etc. relating to him".
  - Health-related correspondence and personal notes, 1739 June 19 - 1750 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Three letters which are pasted together concern pharmaceutical remedies for vomiting and the gout, and are dated June 19, 1739; July 4, 1748; and Sept. 11 1750.
    The 3 sheets of paper placed inside of this folded paper are undated and similarly discuss the gout.
    One paper is labeled as "Cheyne's Essay on the Gout p. 15" (i.e. George Cheyne's 1719 publication).
  - Correspondence to William Farington regarding the death of his relation William Farington and the execution of his will., 1747 July 10 - 1760 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Despite the title of the paper binder, some of the correspondence predates or postdates 1781 significantly. The dates of the letters are:
    July 10, 1747 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington)
    Sept. 28, 1753 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington)
    June 26, 1857 (from Frederick Loch regarding the barring of an entail created by the wife of Sir William Farington)
    Feb. 27, 1760 (to Rev. Farington from his nephew William Farington)
    January 16, 1781 (addressed to Shaw Hall and regarding the execution of a will from Gill S[later?])
    and Jan. 15, 1781 also from Gill S[later?].
  - Correspondence, 1702 December 25 - 1802 March 16 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Dates are:
    1702 December 25 (from Elizabeth Farington to her son Robert Farington in London)
    1762 December 30 (to Rev. Farington)
    April 23 1740; (to Rev. Farington)
    Sept 14 1767
    July 15 1765 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr)
    March 7 1763 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr)
    November 17 1746 (to Rev. Farington from James Parr)
    March 16, 1802
    small note dated July 1, 1803 regarding Rev. Robert Farington's candidacy for the degree of DD at Brasenose College, Oxford
    small note dated March 14, 1802
    July 15, 1760
  - Correspondence, 1738 October 09 - 1746 December 16 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    On first sheet of paper, one side contains correspondence to Rev. Farington from Eliz[abeth] [Gouldsmith?], and the opposite side contains correspondence dated Oct. 9, 1738 from "[your] most affectionate nephew Robert G[willym?]".
    The second piece of paper is addressed to "William Farington Esq at Shaw Hall" from "John Whitley Oct. 5, 1745".
    The third letter is addressed to "Rev. Mr. Farington, Vicar of Leigh" from J. Parr and is dated Dec. 16, 1746.
  - Last Will and Testament of Rev. William Farington; Articles of Agreement between William Farington and George Farington; Personal Correspondence, 1742 May 01 - 1848 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    On front of paper binder, several sections of writing, in similar or identical hands, in pencil, brown ink, and black ink:
    "The Will of my Reverend Grandfather is here /
    Cutting off the entail, by George Farington and his son William afterwards (des Wm: [Kh?]) [?] George Farington (Eldest Brother of my Grandfather William) and his eldest son William - 1 May 1742 /
    and a letter from James Farington, younger brother of the said William and father of the late William the father of James Noel Farington (who died in 1837) to his uncle my Grandfather William - the letter dated May 17th 1755 [?] strange proof of the State she [a lot?] respectable family here [addressed?] to Wm Farington Capt. R.A. August 3rd 1848 /
    Also a letter from Bradshaw ["Bradshaw" here crossed out with pencil and "James" inserted] FF to his uncle my grandfather WF 1857 /
    NB: The will which Sir William made he entails it, naming Each of his cousins my uncles and father-- is in our paper safe or box." William Farington's will is signed by himself, John Lowe, and Bradley [?] and is dated July 4, 1765.
    The Articles of Agreement "between William Farington, son and heir apparent of George Farington of Shaw Hall in the county of Lancaster" is dated May 1, 1742 and contains William Farington and E. Farington's signatures.
    An expense sheet is included and is dated June 17th, 1748 and also contains the date Jan. 24th 1749: "cashe in Mr. Tho[mas] Whittaker's hand to be divided betwixt him and me".
    A letter dated May 17, 1755 from James Farington is pasted onto the stiff paper board which forms a binder for the materials.
    At the bottom of the letter a different hand writes, "The original on the other side from James brother of Sir William, nephew to my good Grandfather Rev. William, and father of the late Grandfather of the present owner of Worden [that] Hall [?] of our family, W. Farington Capt. Aug, 1846".
    This note continues on the stiff paper board: "His (James') brother cast him out of the estate, settling it upon his (James) son William, entailing it upon his uncle the Rev. William [son] in succession. William with his son James Noel cast [off?] the [entail?] from -- -- 1813 / James Noel [married?] Oct 28th 1847, [died?] 6 June 1848."
  - Personal correspondence, notes, and legal document, 1737 May 5 - 1779 April 26 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    A page labeled April 26, 1779 discusses an incident of forced braking and entering at the writer's residence.
    There are two pieces of correspondence, the first is dated December 7, 1766 and is addressed to Rev. Mr. Farington from his nephew R.V.A [Gwillym?] and the second is dated November 27, 1766 and is addressed to the Rev. Mr. Farington from J. Whitakker.
    There is also a copy of a letter dated November 25, 1760 addressed to the soon-to-be-coronated King (i.e. George III) congratulating him, bearing the names of several local vicars.
    Also included is a notarized document signed by Elizabeth Gouldsmyth, widow of Richard Atherton, Esq., granting her brother Rev. William Farington power of attorney and instituting an annuity, signed May 5, 1737.
  - Personal correspondence, notes, and expense records, 1750 August 06 - 1765 April 01 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Included is a letter labeled "Copy of Sr. Wm Farington's Letter from Rome" with heading "Rome April 1, 1765" and signed William Farington.
    The second letter contains a record of expenses and bears date Aug 6, 1750.
    The third sheet of paper is a chart of expenses and events for March 16th - July 3rd 1763.
  - Correspondence between Sir William Meredith and G. Kendal, 1761 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence and personal notes, 1749 June 24 - 1853 March (Box 3, Folder 15)
    First item is a single page, undated of personal notes related to the vicarage of Leigh.
    The second item is a sheet of paper folded in half to produce four pages, on which are written a verse entitled "Thanks for [?] Huswife, addressed to Miss Dolly Grandwell".
    The third item is a single page of notes dated "June 24, 17[4?]7".
    The fourth item is a letter (it is unclear whom the writer or addressee are) reinforced on the backside with rag paper. Because the writing continues onto the second side, it is partially obscured by the transparent rag paper, but the date "23 July 1750" is visible.
    The fifth item is correspondence between Rev. William Farington and his nephew William Farington dated Oct. 3, 1766.
    The sixth item is undated, unsigned correspondence.
    The seventh item consists of two letters, one smaller and one larger contained within a small, transparent paper wrapper on which is written "Copy of a letter from Sir William Farington to my father William Farington his first cousin. This was copied and sent to me by Susan Farington sister [Noel?] Farington". Inside this wrapper is a small letter dated 1772 with the note "This was copied and sent to me (WF) March 1853" in the inner margin. Also pasted inside this wrapper is a larger letter from William Farington dated 14 Dec. 1762.
- Folio 8
  - Scrap paper used as binder, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notes relating to the North Briton periodical, Church History, and a "Meditation for Christmas Day", undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    The first paper is entitled "The Pope's Introduction of those Realms began the first Sunday after Easter 1208" and contains notes on Church history and excommunication.
    The second, third, fourth, and fifth papers contain transcriptions of, or notes relating to, the North Briton periodical (known for its radicalism) issues 50 and 51 and contain the dates June 9, 1768 and May 28, 1768.
    There is also an undated paper entitled "Meditation for Christmas Day".
  - Personal Notes and Correspondence, 1738 June 20 -July 08 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    The first paper is a letter dated "August 20", addressed "Dear Madam" and signed "Mr. Hall".
    The second and third papers have personal notes of a religious nature.
    The fourth paper is folded in half to produce four pages, on which are written "On the Chorus of the Ancient Drama".
    The fifth paper contains notes in Latin,
    the sixth contains a selection entitled "Written in a window of the Saracen's Head in [C]oventry...",
    the seventh contains a transcription of "A Pastoral by Mr. Broome, Astrophel and Daphne",
    the eight contains writing followed by the note, "This is put over an effigy of Dr. Radclif in the new building of University College,
    the ninth contains a "Scotch song" on one side and astronomical data on the other,
    and the tenth is a sheet of paper folded in half with several dates and sections of notes, ranging from May 4, 1675 to February 3, 1731.
  - Document related to the Nomination of a Schoolmaster for the Grammar School at the Parish of Leigh, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Entitled: "The Case of the Vicar and Parish [?] of the Parish of Leigh relating to the Nomination of a Schoolmaster of the School in the Tower and Parish of Leigh aforsaid". At bottom of first page lists four dates of relevance for the history of the grammar school: 18 Sept 1694, 1704, 1726 Nov 2, 1735 April 23
  - Will of Thomas Armstriding, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Will or draft of will of Thomas Armstriding, "Vicar of the parish and the parish Church of [Loy?]land in the County of Lancaster".
  - Personal Notes and Correspondence, 1734 May 18 - June 25 1767 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    First item is a small note dated May 18, 1734
    second item is a small note dated June 25, 1767 with heading "Rec'd this paper from Mr Hartley" regarding "income from the school".
    Third item is a small expense sheet with date 1767 and name "Mr. Whittacker" written on it.